<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antipatterns on VGALTES blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/antipatterns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antipatterns on VGALTES blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/antipatterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo cult</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/cargo-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/cargo-cult/</guid>
      <description>Cargo cult is a movement that is found in societies that believe in often-apocalyptic religious prophecies that predict a return to power, the defeat of enemies, and/or the accumulation of wealth. This movement often occurs in colonial societies.
The first occurrences date from the end of the 19th century in Fiji, but the most important ones are the ones in the Melanesian islands after the World War II. During the war, both sides airdropped supplies and military equipment for their troops that often shared it with the local population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cowboys</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/cowboys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/cowboys/</guid>
      <description>According to the Wikipedia, a cowboy (and a cowgirl) is an animal herder who tends cattle on ranches in North America, traditionally on horseback, and often performs a multitude of other ranch-related tasks. They were quite famous in the 19th century and we can still find them in ranches.
Hollywood adapted the cowboy lifestyle to create some stereotypes, both positive and negative. But, in general, a cowboy was a guy with a gun killing people, either because they were bad guys or because they were defending a good cause.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>