<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circleci on VGALTES blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/circleci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Circleci on VGALTES blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/circleci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using different configuration per stage</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/using-different-configuration-per-stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/using-different-configuration-per-stage/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article we saw how to create a basic deployment pipeline for a serverless application. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to enrich the deployment by allowing to have different values for configuration settings in each stage.
Background The moment your application starts to be a little bit more complex, you need to use configuration settings. These settings can be things like the log level, addresses of external services, usernames and (encrypted) passwords, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a serverless application</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/deploy-serverless-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/deploy-serverless-app/</guid>
      <description>Starting with AWS Lambda is really easy. You can even write a function in the browser! But that&amp;rsquo;s not how you should work on a daily basis. You must have a CI/CD pipeline set up, you probably have two accounts (one for production and another one for development), you need a repeatable and reliable way to create your infrastructure and so on. In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to create a simple continuous delivery pipeline that brings us closer to a professional application development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>