<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pattern Matching on VGALTES blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/pattern-matching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pattern Matching on VGALTES blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/pattern-matching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Partial classification active pattern</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2016-10-17-partial-classification-active-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2016-10-17-partial-classification-active-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Pattern matching is a powerful and amazing characteristic of F#. Actually, is so amazing that Microsoft is starting to port it to C#.
There are different kinds of pattern matching. In this post we&amp;rsquo;re going to take a look at a partial classification active pattern that takes an argument and returns a value.
As its name denotes, is a pattern that partially classificates what you match with it. That means that doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to define all possible options but just one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# by example: FizzBuzz kata rivisited - More on Pattern-Matching</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2015-05-10-fsharp-by-example-fizzbuzz-kata-rivisited-more-on-pattern-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 18:30:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2015-05-10-fsharp-by-example-fizzbuzz-kata-rivisited-more-on-pattern-matching/</guid>
      <description>In the first post of this series we&#39;ve seen a possible implementation for the FizzBuzz kata. In particular, we&#39;ve finished the article with this code for the fizzBuzz function:
https://gist.github.com/vgaltes/edafb6efc55273543a1d
We&#39;ve applied a Tuple pattern to match the tuple created in the match part. We&#39;ve also applied Wildcard matching to discard the values we are not interested in.
In this article we&#39;re going to see how we can solve this problem using another flavors of Pattern-Matching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# by example: FizzBuzz Kata</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2015-04-24-f-example-fizzbuzz-kata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 15:03:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2015-04-24-f-example-fizzbuzz-kata/</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday I started a book club with my friends Samir Talwar and Pedro Moreira Santos (both of them working at Codurance). The book we&#39;ve choseen is &#34;The book of F#&#34;, because we want to learn F#.
After reading the first three chapters we decided to make the FizzBuzz kata to start practicing. In this article I&#39;m going to explain you how we solved the kata trying to explain all the F# syntax we use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>