<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Thoughts on VGALTES blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/random-thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Thoughts on VGALTES blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/random-thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/mentoring/</guid>
      <description>Last September I turned 40. You know, in the movies, when someone turns forty he buys a new brand card, gets divorced and tries something new. I still don&amp;rsquo;t have a car and, although I&amp;rsquo;m not married, I still live with my partner, but I did start something new. In my case, was an old &amp;ldquo;aspiration&amp;rdquo; (I tried it 7 years ago): learning to play guitar. Not that I want to be the next Angus Young but I never had any musical education and I always wanted to be able to play an instrument, especially guitar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The architect</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 17:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/architect/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday was my last day in the project I worked on the last six months. I&#39;ve spent a great time working there, learning a lot of things and improving as a professional.
One of the members of the team, Mark, has the role of technical architect. If you have an agile mindset when you listen the word architect is not unusual that a look of disgust appears on your face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionalism</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 23:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/professionalism/</guid>
      <description>According to Wikipedia, in some cultures the term professional is used as shorthand to describe a particular social stratum of well-educated workers who enjoy considerable work autonomy and who are commonly engaged in creative and intellectually challenging work. According to Google Analytics you probably come from one of these cultures.
I have to admit that when I started to hear the term Craftsmanship I was distrusting, maybe because some of the people that used it tried to use it as a label to put themselves in a higher level than the rest of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t do experiments with your client&#39;s money</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/dont-do-experiments-with-your-clients-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 14:33:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/dont-do-experiments-with-your-clients-money/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you &#34;manage&#34; a development team. Imagine you reach to have a product that your client is reasonably happy with it. Imagine that the architecture of the application is a mess. Imagine that you don&#39;t have any test. Imagine that the performance of the application is clearly improvable. Imagine that you can improve the user experience a lot. Imagine that you UI layer is made in a 14 years old technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>